Massacre Chapter
Part Three
Fluctuation
saa, wasuremashou sono mirai ga
Come, let us forget about the future...
Planning
Takeshi Oikawa
Akihiro Kawamura
Akihiro Yuasa
Original Work ・ Original Story/Supervision
Ryukishi07/07th Expansion
"Higurashi no Naku Koro ni"
"Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai"
mata chinurarete yuku nante
...ending up stained in blood again.
Series Composition
Toshifumi Kawase
Character Design
Overall Animation Supervisor
Kyuuta Sakai
Art Director
Chikako Shibata
Color Design
Shinji Matsumoto
namanurui kaze toguro wo maitara
If the soft wind coils up...
Camera Director
Masayuki Kawaguchi
Editing
Masahiro Matsumura
Music
Kenji Kawai
Sound Director
Hozumi Gouda
sore ga tabun aizu
...that is probably a sign.
nukedashitette
Break free.
Opening Theme
"Naraku no Hana"
(Flower in Hell)
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition
Arrangement
Eiko Shimamiya
Tomoyuki Nakazawa
Takeshi Ozaki
kanashisugiru unmei kara
From your heart-wrenching fate.
Music Producer
Music Production
Mei Yoshikawa
Frontier Works
anata wa naraku no hana ja nai
You are not a flower in hell.
Producers
Mika Nomura
Hiroyuki Oomori
Takeshi Okamura
sonna basho de sakanaide
Don't blossom in such a place.
Animation Producer
Animation Production
Kouji Iijima
Studio Deen
sakanaide
Don't blossom there.
karametorarete ikanaide
Don't get entangled.
oto mo naku tobikau toki no kakera
Fragments of time flutter about without a sound.
Production
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai Production Committee
Director
Chiaki Kon
Hi
gu
ra
shi
no
Na
ku
Koro
ni
Kai
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai
Making a run for it with our group's money?
（男）
組の銭 持ってトンズラとは―
（間宮(まみや)）ハッ
You think you can fuck with us?
（男）ナメたマネ
してくれるじゃねえか　ああ？
（梨花(りか)）羽入(はにゅう)！
Hanyuu!
Hanyuu, where are you!?
羽入　どこ!?
Satoko hasn't come back yet!
（梨花）
沙都子(さとこ)がまだ帰ってこないの！
Crap...
もうっ 肝心な時に
いつもフラフラ出かけてるんだから
She's always off and about when I need her most!
I have a bad feeling about this...
（梨花）
イヤな予感がする　まさか…
It couldn't be...!
God...
神様 どうか… どうか
私の予感が外れていますように
Please...
Please let my premonition be wrong...
Rika?
（沙都子）梨花？
（梨花）あっ
Satoko!
沙都子！
（北条(ほうじょう)）沙都子！
やかん かけっ放しで出よったんな
You left the kettle on when you went out, didn't you!?
You fucking good for nothing!
この だらず！
I'm sorry...
（沙都子）ごめんなさい
You told me to go to the store immediately, so...
“すぐに買いに行け”って
言われたから…
ボケが！
（沙都子）うわっ あっ
Dumbass!
Get your ass in here!
さっさと上がってこい！
Umm...
（沙都子）あの… 梨花
（梨花）あっ んっ？
Rika?
I'm thinking of living in this house from today on.
私(わたくし) 今日から
こっちの家で暮らそうと思いますの
（梨花）沙都子！
Satoko!
My uncle returned.
私の叔父さんが帰ってきましたの
So we made the decision to live in this house together.
だから “こっちの家で
一緒に暮らそう”って―
そういう話になりまして
Satoko!
（北条）沙都子！
早(はよ)う乾きもん持ってこんかい！
Hurry and bring me my snacks!
（沙都子）あっ はい！
Y-Yes!
[Okinomiya Police Station]
Well well...
（大石(おおいし)）これはこれは―
（大石）古手(ふるで)さんから お電話を
頂けるなんて思いませんでした
I never expected to get a phone call from you, Furude-san.
Ooishi.
大石　赤坂(あかさか)と話をしたいのですが…
I want to speak with Akasaka.
Akasaka-san?
（大石）赤坂さんですか？
（梨花）連絡を取りたいのです
I want to get into contact with him.
Akasaka-san isn't in Okinomiya.
（大石）
赤坂さんなら興宮(おきのみや)にはいませんよ
He's at a spa with his wife.
（大石）
奥さんと温泉に行っています
His lodging?
宿？　いやあ 聞いていませんねえ
I haven't heard about that.
Is it something urgent?
何か急用ですか？　あっ もしもし
Hello?
Furude-san?
（大石）古手さん
If I leave this alone...
このまま放っておいたら
また いつもの繰り返し
...things will end up like usual.
The world will get lost in the maze of tragedy.
世界は 悲劇の迷宮に
迷い込んでしまう
I won't give up!
諦めない　まだ手段が残っている
I still have options left!
（入江(いりえ)）山狗(やまいぬ)を動かす？
Mobilize the Yamainu?
It's the only way!
もう それしか方法がないのです
At this rate, Satoko will be completely ruined by her uncle.
このままでは 沙都子はあの叔父に
めちゃくちゃにされてしまう
（鷹野(たかの)）んっ
I've heard the rumors about Teppei Houjou as well.
北条鉄平(てっぺい)さんのうわさは
私も聞いているわ
But wouldn't it be best to contact the police or the Child Counseling Center first?
でも それなら警察か児童相談所に
連絡するのが順序ではなくて？
それでは遅いのです！
They won't act fast enough!
Irie!
入江　去年の沙都子を
思い出してほしいのです！
Please remember the state Satoko was in last year!
（入江）あっ
（梨花）沙都子は また―
Satoko will...
...end up that way again!
あんなふうになってしまうのです
But...
しかし…
山狗を動かすということは―
Mobilizing the Yamainu would mean...
Basically, eliminating her uncle...
つまり 叔父さんを…
The Yamainu were deployed in Hinamizawa for your protection.
（鷹野）山狗は
あなたを警護するために―
雛見沢(ひなみざわ)に配備されているの
それ以外で動かすことは…
We can't utilize them for any other means...
Weren't you close with Satoko as well, Takano?
鷹野だって
沙都子とは仲良しだったはずです！
We share the same wish!
一生のお願いなのです
沙都子を助けてほしいのです！
Please help Satoko!
んっ… 入江先生？
Dr. Irie...
Takano-san.
鷹野さん　梨花ちゃんの頼みを
聞いてあげてください
Please grant Rika-chan's request.
Dr. Irie...
入江先生
ハッ
（入江）沙都子ちゃんは―
Satoko-chan is indispensible for our research as well.
我々の研究にとっても
欠かすことのできない存在です
I ask you as the person in charge here.
ここの責任者として お願いします
リスクばかりで見返りのない仕事ね
A risky job without payoff, huh?
All right.
いいわ　連絡してみます
I'll make some calls.
They can't?
（入江）できない!?
It seems Teppei Houjou is being monitored by the police.
北条鉄平には
警察のマークが付いているらしいの
A woman named Rina Mamiya was killed in Okinomiya recently...
最近 興宮で
間宮リナという女性が殺されて―
その事件に
彼が関与しているんですって
...and they believe him to have been involved in that incident.
So basically...
つまり 山狗を動かせば
警察に気づかれてしまう
...the police will take notice if we mobilize the Yamainu.
ハア 梨花ちゃん
申し訳ないけど―
Rika-chan.
I'm very sorry...
警察のマークが外れるまでは
山狗は手の出しようがないわ
...but until the police finish their investigation...
...the Yamainu can't make a move.
んっ いつになったら
動けるようになるのですか？
So when will they be able to move?
たぶん 早くても綿流しの後
（梨花）ハッ
Probably...
...after Watanagashi at the soonest.
それでは遅い！
That's too late!
I've been cooperating with you two for all this time!
私は お前たちに
ずっと協力してきた！
And yet, even though you have so much power...
なのに
あれだけの力を持ちながら―
...why do you say you can't save Satoko!?
どうして
沙都子を救えないと言うのか！
もういい　よく分かった！
Forget it!
I get it already!
この世界が袋小路だということが
よく分かった！
I know very well that this world is a dead end!
（鷹野）ハッ…
（梨花）お前は―
You go burn to death in the mountains!
山奥で焼かれて死ね！
You go kill yourself with narcotics!
お前は睡眠薬で自殺しろ！
Die! Die!
死ね　死ね　みんな死ねー！
Everyone die!
They were shocked.
２人とも びっくりしてたわ
That's why I told you.
（羽入）だから言ったのです
If you expect too much from fate...
“運命に期待しすぎると
裏切られた時 つらい”と
...it will be hard on you when you're betrayed...
（梨花）
期待するななんて 酷な話よ
How could I not expect something?
A world in which so much went right...
これだけ すべてに恵まれた世界は
初めてだったんだから
...is something I never had before.
This world is finished already.
（羽入）
もう この世界はダメなのです
でも 我慢強く待てば―
But if we wait patiently...
いつかまた 幸運に恵まれた世界が
やってくるはずなのです
...a blessed world should come around eventually.
そして何十年も待つの？
（羽入）あっ
So we wait for another few decades?
Are you telling me to keep repeating worlds that barely last two weeks over and over again?
（梨花）
ほんの２週間ほどの世界を―
何度も何度も
繰り返し続けろと言うの？
That's impossible.
無理よ
その前に
私の頭がどうかしてしまうわ
My mind will break down before it happens.
んっ もうどうでもいい
I don't care anymore.
Not just about this world.
この世界だけじゃない
But about the worlds to come as well.
これからの世界も どうでもいい
I just don't care anymore...
あうう… はうう…
梨花…
Rika...
（レナ）梨花ちゃん
Rika-chan.
Why is Satoko-chan absent, I wonder?
沙都子ちゃん
どうして休んでるのかな？　かな？
Is she sick?
（圭一(けいいち)）病気か？
Rika-chama?
（詩音(しおん)）梨花ちゃま　お願いです
Please!
If something happened to Satoko, please tell me!
沙都子に何かあったんなら
教えてください
Furude-san?
（知恵(ちえ)）古手さん？
（梨花）うるさいなあ
Just shut up.
えっ
（梨花）帰るわ
I'm going home.
ま… 待ちなさい！
W-Wait!
[Staff Room]
Houjou-san's uncle?
（知恵）北条さんの叔父さんが？
そうだったんですか
I see...
So...
で あなたには何ができるの？
...what do you think you can do about it?
あっ ふ… 古手さん？
F-Furude-san...?
これから
北条さんのうちに行ってきます
I will go to Houjou-san's house.
I'll meet with Satoko-chan first...
まずは 沙都子ちゃんに会って
事情を聞いて問題があるようなら…
...ask her about the situation, and if there seems to be a problem...
（梨花）
児童相談所に行ってもムダよ
No use going to the Child Counseling Center.
Satoko has been giving false reports in the past.
沙都子は過去に
ウソの通報をしている
If you don't have solid proof, they won't make a move.
確かな証拠がなければ
相談所は動かない
But...
そこは…
I'm sure if we properly appeal to them...
きっと ちゃんと訴えれば
何とかしてもらえると思います
...they will take some sort of action.
（魅音(みおん)）梨花ちゃん
Rika-chan.
Did Satoko-chan's uncle really return, I wonder?
ほんとに沙都子ちゃんの叔父さんが
帰ってきたのかな？　かな？
（圭一）うわさは聞いている
I heard the story.
昔 沙都子とその兄貴を
さんざん いじめた奴だろ？
Satoko and her brother were abused by him in the past, right?
Calm down everyone.
（知恵）皆さん　落ち着いて
I will go meet Houjou-san right now.
これから 私が
北条さんに会ってきますから
How can we stay calm about this!?
落ち着いてられるわけないでしょ！
You know what Satoko and Satoshi-kun were put through by that bastard, don't you!?
沙都子と悟史(さとし)君が あいつに
どんな目に遭わされてたか―
先生だって知ってるでしょ!?
They were slaved around...
こき使われて 追い詰められて…
Driven into a corner...
And yet...
なのに 私たちは何もできなかった
...we were unable to do anything.
１年前と同じことを
繰り返そうっていうんですか!?
Do you want to repeat what happened a year ago!?
It won't come to that.
そんなことにはなりません　絶対に
I'll make sure of it.
Class Rep.
委員長　私が戻るまで自習です
Put the class on self-study until I return.
Understood.
（魅音）分かりました
Rika...
梨花？
（梨花）これも過去の世界と同じ
This is the same as in past worlds.
The Child Counseling Center won't do a thing...
児童相談所は何もしないし―
私たちは 結局
悲劇を食い止めることができない
...and we are unable to avoid a tragedy from happening.
There was no meaning at all to this world.
（梨花）
この世界には何の意味もなかった
All that's left...
あとは ただ終わるのを待つばかり
...is to wait for it to end.
Who the fuck are you?
なんじゃいね おんどれは！
あっ　私(わたくし) 北条沙都子さんの担任の
知恵と申します
I am Satoko Houjou's teacher Chie.
Is Satoko-san in?
沙都子さんは
いらっしゃいますか？
ああ!?　担任？
Her teacher?
I have something to discuss with Satoko-chan.
沙都子ちゃんに
お話したいことがあるのですが
Satoko has a cold.
沙都子は風邪じゃ！
熱 出しとるんじゃ！
She's got a fever!
I-Is that so...
そ… そうですか
明日は登校できそうですか？
Will she be able to come to school tomorrow?
The fuck should I know!?
知るかいな！　そんなもん
北条さん！
Houjou-san!
（北条）おう 待たせたな
（マージャンパイを転がす音）
Sorry 'bout the wait!
And you just meekly walked away?
（詩音）それで
のこのこ帰ってきたんですか!?
If you don't even try to force your way in...
無理やりにでも家に踏み込んで―
沙都子の無事を確認しなきゃ
意味ないじゃないですか！
...to confirm Satoko's condition, what's the point!?
やめなよ 詩ぃちゃん
知恵先生に そこまではできないよ
Stop it, Shii-chan.
Ms. Chie can't go that far.
I'm going to report this to the principal.
私は校長先生に報告してきます
（魅音）詩音　どこに行く気!?
Shion!
Where are you going?
私が沙都子を助け出す
私は悟史君に頼まれたんだから！
I'm going to get Satoko out of there!
Satoshi-kun asked me to take care of her!
He entrusted her to me!
“沙都子を頼む”って
言われたんだから！
I will save Satoko even if it means I have to kill Teppei Houjou!
北条鉄平を殺してでも
私が沙都子を救い出す！
そうだ 今からあいつを殺しに行く
それが一番手っ取り早い方法です！
That's it...
I'm gonna kill him right now.
That's the quickest solution!
Shii-chan...
詩ぃちゃん
（魅音）詩音　落ち着いて
Shion...
Calm down!
あんたたちが
自分の無力さを嘆いてる間に―
While you are lamenting your inability...
...I will do away with Teppei Houjou.
私は北条鉄平を片づける
If I go to his house right now...
今から家に行って
あいつを殺して―
...and kill the bastard...
1500秒もあれば
何もかも終わらせることができる！
...I can settle this whole matter within 1500 seconds!
No!
ダメ　行かせないよ！
I won't let you go!
人殺しなんかしたって
何の解決にもならない
Resorting to murder won't solve a thing.
We'll only end up suffering even more misfortune!
みんながもっと不幸になるだけだよ
私は 沙都子が
どれほど苦しんできたか知ってる！
I know how much pain Satoko went through!
雛見沢から つまはじきにされて
叔父夫婦に いじめ抜かれて―
She was ostracized by Hinamizawa...
...tortured by her aunt and uncle...
実の兄が行方不明になって
...and her own brother went missing!
それでも負けずに 強くなろうと
頑張ってきたことを知ってる！
And I know how she relentlessly fought on despite all that!
あんないい子に これ以上
つらい思いをさせてたまるか！
I'll be damned if I let such a good kid go through any more hardship!
Hold it.
待ちな
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni
Kai
Step aside, Kei-chan.
どいてください 圭ちゃん
Can't do that.
（圭一）
そうはいかねえなあ　俺には分かる
I can tell.
If you end up killing Satoko's uncle...
沙都子の叔父を殺したら
お前は絶対に後悔する
...you'll regret it for the rest of your life.
I'm prepared for that.
（詩音）覚悟の上です
If I can save Satoko...
沙都子を救えるなら
自分が逮捕されても構いません！
...I don't care if I get arrested!
That isn't true.
それは違うなあ
お前が本当に求めているのは―
What you really wish...
みんなが元どおりに
楽しく暮らす世界のはずだ
...is for everyone to live the happy life we used to.
But by committing murder...
なのに 殺人を犯すことで―
...you will crush any chances of that happening!
お前は その可能性を
台なしにしてしまうんだよ
Get out of my way!
どきなさい！
If you're going to obstruct me...
邪魔をするなら
先に あんたから殺しますよ！
...I'll start by killing you!
How interesting.
面白い　やってもらおうか
Why don't you try it?
You think I'm joking, don't you?
冗談だと思ってるんでしょ？
I'll do it.
私は やりますよ
園崎(そのざき)詩音は やりますよ
Shion Sonozaki will kill you.
I can kill any number of my enemies.
自分の敵は何人だって殺せる
I'm a person capable of doing that!
私は そういうことが
できる人間なんですよ！
Didn't I tell you to do it!?
だから やれって言ってるだろう！
Damn you...
（詩音）この…
Don't, Kei-chan!
ダメだ 圭ちゃん
詩音は本気だよ！
Shion is serious!
Keiichi-kun can handle it.
圭一君なら大丈夫
詩ぃちゃんを説得できる
He'll manage to convince her.
How can you say that!?
（魅音）
なんでそんなこと言えるのさ！
It's okay.
大丈夫
邪魔をするなあ！
Get out of my way!
（詩音）えいっ！
（圭一）ううっ
（レナ）ハア…
Did that calm you down a bit?
少しは落ち着いたか？
I don't know what to do now, either.
今は俺にも
どうしたらいいか分からない
But I'll definitely find a way!
でも 必ず方法を見つけてやる
絶対だ！
Definitely!
So just believe in me!
だから 俺を信じろ！
Leave the rest to us.
（海江田(かいえだ)）あとは我々に任せなさい
Mr. Principal...
（レナ）校長先生
Ms. Chie told me the situation.
事情は知恵先生から聞いた
We will contact the Child Counseling Center immediately...
すぐに児童相談所に連絡し
しかるべき手を打ってもらおう
...and have them take proper measures.
It'll be useless anyway...
どうせムダですよ
Shion-kun.
詩音君　 “どうせ”という言葉を
使った瞬間―
The moment you made that negative statement...
戦いは負けなのだ
...you already lost the battle.
Houjou-kun is a cute pupil of mine.
北条君は わしのかわいい教え子だ
（圭一･レナ）アハッ
I promise me and Ms. Chie will do everything in our power to help her.
（海江田）わしも知恵先生も
最善を尽くすことを約束する
Exactly the same thing happened before.
前にも そっくり同じことが
あったのです
Only that time, Keiichi ended up killing Satoko's uncle...
ただ あの時は―
圭一が叔父を殺したのですけれど
（圭一･レナ）んっ ンフフッ
It seems that was supposed to be Shion's role in this world.
（梨花）この世界では 詩音が
その役回りになるはずだったようね
The fact that Keiichi stopped her was a bit unexpected though.
圭一が止めに入ったのは
意外だったけど
Rika?
（羽入）梨花？
I know.
分かってる
（羽入）あっ
I told you, right?
言ったでしょ
“もう何も望まない”って
I'm not hoping for anything anymore.
I see...
（圭一）そうか　ダメだったのか
So it didn't work.
They were contacted by the principal...
校長先生から連絡を受けて―
...and it seems the Child Counseling Center people went to Satoko's house...
児童相談所の人が 沙都子の家に
行ってくれたそうなんだけど―
Satoko herself apparently answered she didn't need help...
肝心の沙都子が
“助けなんか必要ない”
...and that she wasn't being abused.
“自分は虐待なんか受けてない”
って答えたんだって
Why didn't Satoko seek out help?
どうして沙都子は
助けを求めなかったんだ？
Shion told me.
詩音が言ってた
Satoko feels that Satoshi disappearance...
沙都子は悟史がいなくなったのは
自分のせいだと思ってる
...was her fault.
She didn't have the power to support herself...
自分に耐える力がなくて
悟史に甘えきってしまった
...so she emotionally depended on Satoshi.
And that's what drove Satoshi against the wall.
そのことが悟史を
追い詰めてしまった
誰の力も借りずに耐えることが―
She probably feels that enduring this without relying on others...
...is atonement for what happened to Satoshi-kun.
悟史君への
罪滅ぼしになると思ってるんだね
You know...
レナはね さっき詩ぃちゃんが
言ってたようなこと―
...I was kinda worried that you might have been the one to say the kind of things Shii-chan did earlier.
圭一君が
言い出すんじゃないかなって―
ちょっと心配してたんだ
Since Shion threw a fuss before I could...
詩音が先に騒いでくれたから
俺は冷静になれたのさ
...I was able to keep my cool.
Besides...
それに 俺はずっと前に―
I have this feeling...
...that a long time ago...
本当に自分の手で 沙都子の
叔父を殺したような気がするんだ
...I really killed Satoko's uncle with my own hands.
And the conclusion couldn't have been worse.
そして 結果は最悪だった
I don't know Satoko's uncle at all.
俺は 沙都子の叔父を
まったく知らない
But...
でも このまま放っておいたら
ダメなんだ！
...I can't just let this go on!
Since Satoko herself doesn't seek help...
本人が助けを求めない以上
俺たちが何とかしなくちゃ！
...we have to be the ones to act!
（レナ）そうだね
That's right.
No matter the challenge...
“どんな難問でも力を合わせれば
きっといい方法が思いつく”
...if we combine our strength, we can think of a good way.
昔 誰かに―
I get the feeling someone told me that in the past.
そう教えてもらったような
気がするよ
Dunno who it was...
誰だか知らないが
それをレナに教えた奴は立派だな
...but whoever told you that must've been a cool guy.
But then...
（圭一）とは言ったものの―
What on earth should we do?
一体 どうすりゃいいのかなあ
What are you thinking about?
（伊知郎(いちろう)）
さっきから何考えてるんだ？
たたき売りオークションのことか？
The auction sale?
んっ　父さん　あのさ…
Dad...
Say...
I see.
（伊知郎）そうか
大変なことになってるんだなあ
Things have gotten pretty bad.
Keiichi?
（藍子(あいこ)）圭一　暴力だけはダメよ
Violence is out of the question.
Like a surprise attack, or the perfect crime...
闇討ちとか 完全犯罪とか
そんなこと考えてないよ
I'm not thinking about anything like that.
（藍子）はいっ
Here.
There are many kinds of fights in this world...
（伊知郎）世の中には
いろいろな戦いがあるが―
ルールにのっとって戦わなければ
周りの支持は得られない
...but if you don't stick to the rules...
...you won't win support from the people around you.
あっ
（伊知郎）つまり―
In other words...
...the way to go about it is determined from the start.
方法は初めから決まっているんだ
You mean we should go appeal to the Child Counseling Center?
（魅音）
あたしたちで児童相談所に訴える？
That's right.
そうさ　向こうが事情を
把握してないんだから―
They don't have a clear grasp of the situation.
We have to explain it to them in detail.
それを きちんと
説明しなくちゃならないんだ
That seems to be the proper course of action.
確かに それが正しい手順だよね
An attack from the front, huh?
真正面からの正攻法か
Let's go!
（詩音）行きましょ！
You'll come with us right, Rika-chan?
（圭一）
梨花ちゃんも一緒に来るよな？
Do you really think you can save Satoko from her miserable fate?
本当に 沙都子を
不幸な運命から救えると思うの？
I said this before, right?
前にも言ったろ
You can alter fate with your own hands.
“運命は自分の手で
変えることができるんだ”ってな
（梨花）いいわ
Fine.
そうこなくっちゃ
That's the way!
Rika...
梨花　いいのですか？
Are you sure?
I know this is meaningless.
ムダだってことは分かってる
I'm only going to observe their struggle.
ただ 圭一たちがどうあがくか
見物させてもらうだけ
世界が終わるまでの暇つぶしよ
Just killing time until this world ends.
That is a misunderstanding.
（相談員）それは誤解です
We are actively handling Houjou-san's case.
（相談員）
北条さんの件は現在 対応中です
It's not like we're neglecting her or leaving her to her fate.
見殺しとか放置とか
そういうわけではないんですよ
But you went back without acting yesterday, right?
でも 昨日の時点では
何もせずに帰られてますよね
I can't go into details for privacy reasons...
詳細はプライバシーがあるので
お話しできませんが―
...but we got a grasp of the situation.
事情は伺ってきました
To make sure the Houjou parent and child live out a wholesome life...
北条さん親子が健全な生活を
送れるよう―
引き続き対応を…
（詩音）親子じゃなくて―
...we are continuously...
They aren't parent and child!
叔父と姪(めい)です！
They are uncle and niece!
ほんとに事態を
把握してるんですか!?
Do you really have an understanding of the situation!?
詩音！
Shion!
Excuse me.
失礼しました　そのとおりですね
You are right.
In any case...
とにかく 親権者と児童が
健全な生活を送れるよう指導中です
We are supervising to make sure the child and her caretaker live out a wholesome life.
The uncle neglected Satoko-chan for over a year.
叔父さんは沙都子ちゃんを
１年以上も放置してたんですよ
Could you still call him her caretaker?
それでも
親権者って言えるんですか？
In the Civil Code...
民法では 親権の喪失について
定めがありますよね？
...there are some regulations as to the capabilities of a caretaker, right?
Wouldn't Teppei Houjou's child neglect...
育児放棄をしていた北条鉄平は
それに該当しないんですか？
...be a breach of those regulations?
Satoko hasn't come to school for two days!
沙都子は 昨日も今日も
登校してきてないんです
Please don't take Satoko's words to heart!
沙都子の言葉を
うのみにしないでください
I will let our child welfare specialist in charge know...
皆さんから訴えがあったことは―
...that you all have come to appeal here.
担当の児童福祉士さんに
伝えておきます
Thank you for your valuable information.
貴重な お話を
ありがとうございました
I sure wonder if they're going to bother listening to us.
（魅音）あれで
話を聞いてもらえたか 微妙だねえ
We might as well have been talking to a wall!
あんなんじゃ 壁に向かって
独り言を言っているのと―
変わらないじゃないですか！
This is the proper way to handle this.
私たちのやり方は
間違ってないはずだよ
But I suppose our zeal and distress...
でも 本当の担当者の人には―
...will be lost on the actual person in charge.
私たちの熱意や危機感は
伝わらないだろうね
I figure if my name comes up...
うちの名前を出せば―
...it will be a different ball game for them.
向こうの対応も
違ってくるんだろうけどね
The Sonozaki family is in conflict with the Houjou family, after all.
園崎家は北条家と対立してるから
It's all that old hag's fault.
鬼婆(おにばば)が悪いんですよ
How long does she intend to continue the dam war!?
一体 いつまでダム戦争
やってるつもりなんですか！
I'm sorry, Rika-chan.
すまん 梨花ちゃん
でかい口たたいといて打つ手なしだ
I let my big mouth run, but I can't do a thing.
（梨花）信じない
（圭一）んっ
I don't believe it.
You told me before...
（梨花）圭一は私に教えてくれた
...that fate could be defeated.
“運命は
打ち破ることができる”って
That's why...
だから 圭一が
そんなことを言うなんて―
...I don't believe...
...what you just said.
私は信じない
あっ 梨花ちゃん
Rika-chan...
I don't want to give up after all.
（梨花）私 やっぱり諦めたくない
I want to save Satoko.
沙都子を救いたい
圭一　助けて！
Keiichi!
Help her!
Help Satoko out of this fate!
この運命から沙都子を助けて
お願い！
I beg of you!
そうだな
You're right.
ここが踏ん張りどころだ
We should stand firm right now.
Keiichi...
圭一
ンッ！　おかげで目が覚めたぜ
You opened my eyes!
This isn't the time to be disheartened.
ここはしょぼくれるところじゃねえ
怒り狂うところだ
We should be burning with rage!
なあ そうだろ？　みんな
Isn't that right everyone!?
But...
でも これからどうするの？
次の手があるの？
What should we do now?
Is there anything we can do next?
Of course!
もちろんさ　しかも そいつは―
And it's looking to be a tactic I happen to be very skilled at!
どうやら 俺が
最も得意とする戦術になりそうだぜ
Cast
Keiichi Maebara
Rena Ryuuguu
Mion Sonozaki
Shion Sonozaki
Satoko Houjou
Rika Furude
Hanyuu
Souichiro Hoshi
Mai Nakahara
Satsuki Yukino
Mika Kanai
Yukari Tamura
Yui Horie
anata no nakigara ni tsuchi wo kakeru
I cover your corpse with soil...
Cast
Kuraudo Ooishi
Kyousuke Irie
Miyo Takano
Teppei Houjou
Rina Mamiya
Rumiko Chie
Principal Kaieda
Ichirou Maebara
Aiko Maebara
Consultor
Man
Chafuurin
Toshihiko Seki
Miki Itou
Katsuhisa Houki
Misa Watanabe
Fumiko Orikasa
Yousuke Akimoto
Yasunori Matsumoto
Naoko Matsui
Risa Mizuno
Atsushi Ono
sore ga kinjirareteita toshitemo
...even though that may have been forbidden.
junsui na manazashi no kairaku ni wa
There was a temptation you could not hide...
kakushikirenai yuuwaku ga atta
...in your pure, blissful eyes.
doushite tsumi ga aru no darou
Why does sin exist?
Ending Theme
"Taishou a"
(Target a)
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition/
Arrangement
doushite batsu ga aru no darou
Why does punishment exist?
hone no saki wa amari ni mo shiroku
That blindingly white tip of the bone...
mugen ni tsuzuku yami wo sasotta
...invited the infinite darkness.
Scenario
Fumihiko Shimo
Storyboards
Episode Direction
Tatsuya Abe
Daisuke Tsukushi
nani mo kamo ga azayaka ni miete
I can see everything clearly now.
Animation Supervisor
Animation Supervision Assistance
Hirofumi Morimoto
Chigai Okado
sugu ni kieteshimau
It will soon vanish.
Animation Production
Studio Deen
Production
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai Production Committee
© 2007 Ryukishi07/Hinamizawa Three Great Houses
（梨花）ああ
とってもとってもまずいのです
"This is really, really bad..."
"What's the matter?"
（羽入）何がまずいのですか？
"I haven't done any of my summer vacation homework..."
（梨花）夏休みの宿題を
全然やっていないのです
If this is your predicament...
（羽入）と思っているあなたへ
ベリーグッドなお知らせなのです
...we have a very good announcement for you!
The star of Hinamizawa, Keiichi Maebara...
（梨花）あなたに代わって
我が雛見沢の星 前原(まえばら)圭一が―
...will accept requests to do your homework for you!
あなたの宿題を
お引き受けいたしますのです
（羽入）へえ！
（梨花）１教科につき１万円
10,000 yen per subject.
There is a limit to the number of applications...
お申込み人数には限りがあるので
定員になり次第 締め切るのです
...so registration will close as soon as capacity is reached!
（羽入）ほ… 本当なのですか!?
Really!?
（梨花）フッ ウソよ
（羽入）は… はうう…
I lied.
Next time, the Massacre Chapter, Part Four.
（羽入）次回 皆殺し編 其の四
「交渉」
"Negotiation."
You could at least do your own homework.
（梨花）
自分の宿題くらい自分でやりなさい
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai
Next time
Massacre Chapter
Part Four
Negotiation